<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>72 on 五饼二鱼</title>
        <link>http://git.freegmy.com/categories/72/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 72 on 五饼二鱼</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Simon Gao</copyright><atom:link href="http://git.freegmy.com/categories/72/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title></title>
        <link>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;这个词有两个意思，大小写意思不同。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在英语中，单词 &amp;ldquo;catholic&amp;rdquo; 和 &amp;ldquo;Catholic&amp;rdquo; 的区别主要在于字母大小写，这导致了不同的意义和用途：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;catholic&lt;/strong&gt;（小写的 &amp;ldquo;c&amp;rdquo;）：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;这个词源自希腊语 &amp;ldquo;katholikos&amp;rdquo;，意思是 &amp;ldquo;普遍的&amp;rdquo; 或 &amp;ldquo;全体的&amp;rdquo;。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在一般用法中，&amp;ldquo;catholic&amp;rdquo; 用来形容广泛、包容或普遍的特性。例如，在某些英语表达中，&amp;ldquo;catholic taste&amp;rdquo; 指的是广泛或多样的品味。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在宗教语境中，它也可以用来描述那些符合普世或普遍基督教信仰的教义和实践，不特指任何特定的教派。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catholic&lt;/strong&gt;（大写的 &amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;）：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;当 &amp;ldquo;Catholic&amp;rdquo; 首字母大写时，它专指罗马天主教会，一个具体的宗教组织。这包括所有承认教宗为最高精神领袖的基督徒。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;这个用法涉及到与罗马天主教会有关的一切，包括教义、礼仪、传统和教会管理。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;因此，使用时需要注意区分这两个词的含义，尤其是在涉及具体宗教背景或讨论时。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Viewing North Korea from a &lt;strong&gt;biblical perspective&lt;/strong&gt; requires us to apply biblical principles of justice, compassion, hope, and the sovereignty of God to the unique situation of the nation. Here are some key themes to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-recognizing-the-image-of-god-in-every-person&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Recognizing the Image of God in Every Person&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them.”&lt;/em&gt; (Genesis 1:27, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“于是神照着自己的形象造人，乃是照着他的形象造男造女。”&lt;/em&gt; (创世记 1:27, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every North Korean, regardless of their circumstances or government system, is created in the image of God. This gives them inherent dignity and worth. Despite living under oppressive conditions, they are loved by God and deserve respect, compassion, and advocacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-responding-to-oppression-and-injustice&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Responding to Oppression and Injustice&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Give justice to the weak and the fatherless; maintain the right of the afflicted and the destitute.”&lt;/em&gt; (Psalm 82:3, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“你们当为贫寒的人和孤儿伸冤，为困苦和穷乏的人施行公义。”&lt;/em&gt; (诗篇 82:3, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The regime’s oppression, injustice, and lack of basic freedoms contrast sharply with biblical teachings on justice. Christians are called to be voices for the voiceless, advocating for the oppressed, and working toward justice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-praying-for-governments-and-leaders&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Praying for Governments and Leaders&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“First of all, then, I urge that supplications, prayers, intercessions, and thanksgivings be made for all people, for kings and all who are in high positions, that we may lead a peaceful and quiet life, godly and dignified in every way.”&lt;/em&gt; (1 Timothy 2:1-2, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“我劝你第一要为万人恳求、祷告、代求、祝谢，为君王和一切在位的也该如此，使我们可以敬虔端正、平安无事地度日。”&lt;/em&gt; (提摩太前书 2:1-2, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christians are called to pray for the leaders of North Korea, even if their actions seem contrary to God’s will. Pray for their hearts to be softened, for wisdom to govern justly, and for the nation to experience peace and transformation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-having-compassion-for-the-suffering&#34;&gt;4. &lt;strong&gt;Having Compassion for the Suffering&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“If one member suffers, all suffer together; if one member is honored, all rejoice together.”&lt;/em&gt; (1 Corinthians 12:26, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“若一个肢体受苦，所有的肢体就一同受苦；若一个肢体得荣耀，所有的肢体就一同快乐。”&lt;/em&gt; (哥林多前书 12:26, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As part of the global church, we are spiritually connected to believers in North Korea who are suffering persecution. Christians should stand in solidarity, offering prayer, support, and advocacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-trusting-in-gods-sovereignty&#34;&gt;5. &lt;strong&gt;Trusting in God’s Sovereignty&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The king&amp;rsquo;s heart is a stream of water in the hand of the Lord; he turns it wherever he will.”&lt;/em&gt; (Proverbs 21:1, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“王的心在耶和华手中，好像陇沟的水，随意流转。”&lt;/em&gt; (箴言 21:1, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the hardships in North Korea, God is sovereign and able to bring change in His timing. Christians are called to trust in God’s ultimate plan and work faithfully while waiting for His intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-proclaiming-the-gospel&#34;&gt;6. &lt;strong&gt;Proclaiming the Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.”&lt;/em&gt; (Matthew 28:19, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“所以，你们要去，使万民作我的门徒，奉父、子、圣灵的名给他们施洗。”&lt;/em&gt; (马太福音 28:19, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharing the Gospel is a command for all Christians. Though North Korea is one of the most difficult places for mission work, the Gospel remains a source of hope for the people there. Pray for opportunities for the Gospel to reach them and for the growth of the underground church.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-hope-for-redemption&#34;&gt;7. &lt;strong&gt;Hope for Redemption&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Biblical Principle&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.”&lt;/em&gt; (Revelation 21:4, ESV)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“神要擦去他们一切的眼泪，不再有死亡，也不再有悲哀、哭号、疼痛，因为以前的事都过去了。”&lt;/em&gt; (启示录 21:4, 新标点和合本)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;North Korea’s current suffering is not the end of the story. God’s kingdom promises a future where all suffering is wiped away. This provides hope and a reminder to work toward God’s justice while anticipating His ultimate renewal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-should-we-respond&#34;&gt;How Should We Respond?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pray&lt;/strong&gt; for North Korean leaders, the suffering people, and the spread of the Gospel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advocate&lt;/strong&gt; for justice and human rights for the oppressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Support&lt;/strong&gt; organizations that aid North Korean refugees and underground believers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust&lt;/strong&gt; in God’s timing and sovereignty over the nation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;May we always seek God’s will in how we view and engage with North Korea, striving to show His love and justice in all things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title></title>
        <link>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://git.freegmy.com/p/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;在圣经中，“乐园”是一个重要的概念，通常指的是一个与神同在的美好地方，义人在死后可以进入这个地方。以下是“乐园”在圣经中的一些具体描述和解释：
&lt;img src=&#34;http://git.freegmy.com/Pasted%20image%2020240708183000.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;乐园的圣经依据&#34;&gt;乐园的圣经依据
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;耶稣在十字架上的应许&lt;/strong&gt;：
在路加福音23:43，耶稣对悔改的强盗说：“我实在告诉你，今日你要同我在乐园里了。”这里的“乐园”被理解为义人在死后立刻进入的神同在的地方。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;保罗的异象&lt;/strong&gt;：
在哥林多后书12:2-4，保罗提到他被提到第三层天和乐园，听见隐秘的言语：“我认得一个在基督里的人，他前十四年被提到第三层天上去。或在身内，我不知道，或在身外，我也不知道，只有神知道。我认得这人，或在身内，或在身外，我都不知道，只有神知道。他被提到乐园里，听见隐秘的言语，是人不可说的。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;启示录中的乐园&lt;/strong&gt;：
启示录2:7提到：“圣灵向众教会所说的话，凡有耳的，就应当听。得胜的，我必将神乐园中生命树的果子赐给他吃。”这里的乐园被描述为神的圣所，义人可以在那里享受生命树的果子。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;乐园的理解&#34;&gt;乐园的理解
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“乐园”在基督教神学中有几个层面的理解：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;死后居所&lt;/strong&gt;：
乐园通常被理解为义人在死后立刻进入的地方，在那里他们与神同在，享受安慰和祝福。这个地方与天堂密切相关，可能被视为天堂的一个部分或入口。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;亚伯拉罕的怀里&lt;/strong&gt;：
在路加福音16章提到乞丐拉撒路被带到亚伯拉罕的怀里，这个地方也常常被理解为乐园，义人在死后进入的安慰之所。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;终极的乐园&lt;/strong&gt;：
最终的乐园或新天新地将是在神的最终计划中，义人与神永远同在的完美新创造。这是启示录21-22章中描述的新天新地和新耶路撒冷，那里没有痛苦、死亡和罪恶。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;总结&#34;&gt;总结
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;乐园在圣经中的指涉包括：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;耶稣对悔改强盗的应许&lt;/strong&gt;：义人在死后立刻进入的神同在的地方。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;保罗的异象&lt;/strong&gt;：一种属灵的经历和启示。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;启示录中的描述&lt;/strong&gt;：最终义人与神同在的完美新创造。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;乐园总体上是指义人死后与神同在的安慰和祝福之所，是信徒的盼望和最终归宿。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
